Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/kaliewhitsett (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Account Management Advertising Advertising Sales

Honors-Awards

INMA Best Public Relations of Community Service Campaign - Second Place

United States Charity Campaign

Design Award Inland Press Association Award

Bronze Award

STAR Award Recipient

Kalie Whitsett

VP | Digital & Creative

Southlake, Texas, United States

Summary

Highly-accomplished, creative strategy and marketing professional with a quantifiable record of consistent growth in market share, profitability, and client satisfaction. Valued, 20+ year professional with success in the development of project charters, marketing activities, social media content, communications strategies, project milestones, status reports, resource plans, and budgets. An industry expert in the design and delivery of creative development experiences for clients including FD Luxe, Savor Dallas, Custom Publications. Process improvement expert delivering increased efficiency to individual and enterprise-wide products and programs. A key developer of revenue-generating lines of business and increased revenue in existing and new markets. Trusted mentor to the team, division, and departmental managers with a focused effort on professional development. Manager of multi-million dollar budget including purchase and implementation costs. Strong research/data analyst with expert knowledge of industry competition and trends.

Experience

Augustine Agency
VP | Digital & Creative
September 2021 - Present (3 years 6 months)
California | Nevada | Texas

Lifeblue

Marketing Account Director | Brand Innovation | Strategy June 2020 - December 2021 (1 year 7 months)

Plano, Texas, United States

Eighty Three Creative 2 years 9 months

Vice President Operations November 2018 - June 2020 (1 year 8 months)

Dallas, Texas, United States

Director of Client Services
October 2017 - November 2018 (1 year 2 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

DMNmedia

7 years 7 months

General Manager of Creative Strategy and Client Services June 2016 - July 2017 (1 year 2 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Leading a team of 70 staff, strategized and developed innovative sales and marketing campaigns through concept development, data mining, asset management, optimization through targeting, and reporting metrics. Managed cradle-to-grave account fulfillment including client engagement, creative management, order entry, and final invoicing incorporating management of post-sale process of all workflow, systems and policies. Spearheaded creation and implementation of Account Management team with primary goals to deliver exceptional client service and revenue generation resulting in major increases in revenue, client engagement and up-sell opportunities. Collaborated across multiple business lines throughout project lifecycles to meet customer requirements. Performed final QA/QC for quality of client materials from presentation through final production. Acted as Hiring Manager and staffing policy advisor.

Senior Director of Client Services January 2010 - May 2016 (6 years 5 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Managed and mentored a team of 22 designers, engineers, analysts, and interns. Led the conversion of an in-house marketing and advertising section to an externally-facing creative agency expanding market share by 20% in the first year. Managed migration for all print, digital, and direct mail systems to deliver and integrated single-entry point for all sales engagements. Owned all end-to-end account fulfillment including creative asset management, order entry, and final invoice delivery. Managed and mitigated risks, ensured program prioritization, decided trade-offs, and balanced enterprise requirements against constraints. Participated in requirements gathering, process re-engineering, design, external vendor selection and on-going vendor management, system design, testing, deployment. Participated in the development of long-term strategic utilization plans for multimedia systems.

A. H. Belo Director of Creative Services July 1994 - June 2017 (23 years)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Core Competencies:

CREATIVE STRATEGY: Developed, planned, and executed creative marketing campaign for SAVOR (Dallas Food & Wine Festival) including 6K end-users, 50 local chefs, 75 restaurants, and over 30M online impressions through marketing, advertising, PR, and social media. Using data-driven digital print ROP, email and an inviting social marketing campaign; conceptualized and delivered the Dallas Furniture Week; a creative, targeted special section using enhanced design and photography to engage readers in during furniture "season" during the months of February and March. This feature resulted in the highest Q1 revenue for one retailer and increased revenue for the balance of clients. Developed and delivered unique marketing campaign to target readers for Dallas/Fort Worth Restaurant & Spa Week that coincided with Tax-Free Weekend resulting in increased retail revenue and client satisfaction. Using print, digital, email, social, and video engagement; delivered a high-impact marketing and engagement campaign to TDMN charities resulting in \$66,000 above YOY, with 20% more donors than 2015 and increased contributions exceeding \$1.2M and 1,600 donors.

TEAM DEVELOPMENT AND LEADERSHIP: Restructured Sales and Marketing Division by developing and implementing the 3 aspects of "post-sale"; creative services, advertising operations, and account management. Creation of this group resulting in stronger collaboration and communication in intra-divisional teams and increased productivity and client satisfaction. Developed strategy to outsource production of the creative deliverables while maintaining quality of internal design resources including outsourcing vendor identification, technical architecture asset transfer, training impacted teams and internal clients, and the launch of the overall project resulting in savings of over \$750K annually.

A.H. Belo General Manager of Creative Servcies 1995 - 2017 (22 years)

The Dallas Morning News
Client Services Manager
May 2008 - January 2010 (1 year 9 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Led marketing and creative design campaigns for over 40 existing clients and a team of 25 designers and staff. Maintained and increased book-of-business through aggressive engagement using Customer Relationship Management (CRM) tools and personnel network. Created and directed a dynamic range of ideas and designs to ensure creative execution supported brand strategy. Lead multidisciplined working groups in the development of new content. Launched creative rate initiative resulting in surpassed, defined goals by 175% within initial launch quarter. Identified and managed technical project dependencies and critical path items. Reviewed and approved all campaign changes and user-story updates. Ensured compliance with all customer design and interactivity requirements.

The Dallas Morning News
Creative Director
January 1995 - February 2008 (13 years 2 months)
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Led a team of 12 graphic designers and data analysts to create consistent design solutions for multiple sections of The DMN. Planned, developed, and executed all creative advertising and marketing strategies for multiple stakeholders. Communicated team concepts and solutions to Section Chiefs and other stakeholders. Created and managed dynamic working groups to ensure efficient progress of workflow and deadlines. Mentored a team of designers, engineers, assistants, and interns by encouraging innovation, teamwork, inclusion, exploration, and diversity. Worked closely with project owners and stakeholders to discern needs, develop strategies, and providing feedback. Performed needs assessments for multiple, large-scale, design projects. Assured integrity of DMN brand for all advertising, promotional, and marketing endeavors across multiple platforms including digital and print. Developed and managed \$2M budget.

Education

The University of Texas at Arlington
Bachelor of Arts - BA, Marketing / Business · (1991 - 1995)